♪The spring breeze outside the window moves the stream♪
نسيم الربيع خارج النافذة يحرك التيار ♪
♪Who is disturbed by the williow catkins?♪
من ينزعج من طيور الصفصاف؟
♪You're there when I look back, toying with my heart♪
♪ أنت هناك عندما أنظر إلى الوراء ، ألعب بقلبي
♪Everything has become an ornament♪
كل شيء أصبح زخرفة ♪
♪A pair of lovebirds are flying under the roof in the drizzling rain♪
♪ زوج من طيور الحب تحلق تحت السقف تحت المطر المتساقط
♪Whose secrets have drifted to the chamber?♪
أسرار من انجرفت إلى الغرفة؟ ♪
♪The night when the moon shines, I'll have a drink with you♪
♪ في الليلة التي يشرق فيها القمر ، سأشرب معك
♪Let's keep each other company for the rest of our lifes♪
♪ لنحتفظ ببعضنا البعض لبقية حياتنا
♪The mountain and water carry me through my lifetime relationship♪
الجبل والماء يحملني عبر علاقة حياتي ♪
♪Oh, wind and rain, you're as romantic as spring♪
♪ أوه ، الرياح والمطر ، أنت رومانسي مثل الربيع ♪
♪Like the star and the moon, I wish you all well♪
♪ كالنجم والقمر أتمنى لكم كل خير ♪
♪Don't think about him, I'm right by your side♪
♪ لا تفكر فيه ، أنا بجانبك على حق
♪Oh, my dream keeps changing because of you♪
♪ أوه ، حلمي يتغير بسببك
♪I'm still waiting for you to look at me♪
♪ ما زلت أنتظر منك أن تنظر إلي ♪
♪It's hard to let go once one falls in love♪
♪ من الصعب التخلي عنها بمجرد أن يقع المرء في الحب
♪My life is not wasted while being with you♪
لا تضيع حياتي وأنا معك ♪
=Choice Husband=
= اختيار الزوج =
=Episode 13=
= الحلقة 13 =
General Qin, you've worked hard.
الجنرال تشين ، لقد عملت بجد.
Why did you come back suddenly?
لماذا عدت فجأة؟
(Qin Zuze) Your Majesty.
(تشين زوز) جلالة الملك.
Is it right
هل هذا صحيح
for an educated person to disobey one's own mother?
للمثقف أن يعصي أمه؟
General Qin, I disagree.
الجنرال تشين ، أنا لا أوافق.
How dare you
كيف تجرؤ
create trouble
خلق مشكلة
in the royal court?
في الديوان الملكي؟
Let him go.
دعه يذهب.
How dare a eunuch interrupt me
كيف يجرؤ الخصي على مقاطعي
when I'm speaking.
عندما أتحدث.
We return this time
نعود هذه المرة
to get rid of the vile people
للتخلص من الحقير
by Your Majesty's side.
بجانب جلالتك.
My loyalty can be seen by all.
يمكن للجميع رؤية ولائي.
(Gathering of Brilliance)
(تجمع الذكاء)
This way, please.
(تجمع الذكاء) بهذه الطريقة ، من فضلك.
Miss, the trainer is here.
آنسة ، المدرب هنا.
Shen Xiao, greet him.
شين شياو ، تحيته.
Greetings, Sir.
تحية سيدي.
Is he learning martial arts at such a young age?
هل يتعلم فنون الدفاع عن النفس في هذه السن المبكرة؟
He's not young.
إنه ليس شابًا.
We need to educate children
نحن بحاجة لتعليم الأطفال
when they are young.
عندما يكونون صغارًا.
Mother.
الأم.
I saw him before.
رأيته من قبل.
Where?
أين؟
We put him on our gate.
وضعناه على بوابتنا.
Grandfather said the fiercer he looks,
قال الجد أنه يبدو أكثر شراسة ،
the better he can guard the house.
كان بإمكانه حراسة المنزل بشكل أفضل.
Sir, can you guard the house?
سيدي ، هل يمكنك حراسة المنزل؟
Miss Shen. Young Master is too precious.
ملكة جمال شين.  السيد الشاب ثمين للغاية.
I'm afraid he cannot withstand
أخشى أنه لا يستطيع الصمود
the training.
التدريب.
Please look for someone else.
الرجاء البحث عن شخص آخر.
Sir, he's just a child!
سيدي ، إنه مجرد طفل!
Don't mind him!
لا مانع منه!
Next person.
الشخص التالي.
Mother, his viciousness
أمي ، قوته
can really guard the house.
يمكن حقا حراسة المنزل.
Miss Shen, please find someone else.
آنسة شين ، من فضلك اعثر على شخص آخر.
Miss Shen.
ملكة جمال شين.
Mother, he's so ugly!
أمي ، إنه قبيح جدًا!
Farewell.
وداع.
Sir...
سيد...
Here.
هنا.
- Xiao!
- شياو! - شياو!
Xiao.
شياو.
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
I...
أنا...
Xiao.
شياو.
Well...
نحن سوف...
Xiao, wake up!
شياو ، استيقظ!
Xiao, wake up.
شياو ، استيقظ.
Miaomiao.
مياومياو.
I came over as soon as I heard the news.
جئت بمجرد أن سمعت الخبر.
How is Xiao?
كيف حال شياو؟
Perhaps he is exhausted from the training.
ربما يكون منهكًا من التدريب.
This is...
هذا هو...
I have ginseng, deer antlers and cordyceps.
لدي الجينسنغ وقرون الغزلان وكورديسيبس.
Feed him more.
أطعمه أكثر.
You are really generous.
انت حقا كريم.
Mother.
الأم.
You're awake?
انت مستيقظ؟
Xiyuan, you're here.
شيوان ، أنت هنا.
Xiao.
شياو.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Who made you suffer?
من جعلك تعاني؟
I'll teach him a lesson.
سأعلمه درسا.
It's not anyone's fault.
ليس خطأ أحد.
Mother and Master only did it for my sake.
الأم والسيد فعلوا ذلك من أجلي فقط.
Look. He's really considerate.
نظرة.  إنه حقاً يراعي مشاعر الآخرين.
His kindness
لطفه
is just like mine.
هو تماما مثل لي.
You too.
أنت أيضاً.
Xiao is a premature child.
شياو طفل مبتسر.
He is weak.
هو ضعيف.
You should take it slow
يجب أن تأخذ الأمر ببطء
when it comes to learning martial arts.
عندما يتعلق الأمر بتعلم فنون الدفاع عن النفس.
Xiao.
شياو.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
What do you want to do when you grow up?
ماذا تريد أن تفعل عندما تكبر؟
I want...
أريد...
I want to eat bayberries.
أريد أن آكل التوت.
What's so hard about that?
ما الصعب في ذلك؟
The Song family has an orchard that's dozens of mu big.
تمتلك عائلة Song بستانًا يبلغ حجمه عشرات المو كبيرة.
It covers half of the outskirts in the north of the city.
تغطي نصف ضواحي شمال المدينة.
You can have
بإمكانك أن تأخذ
as many bayberries as you want,
العديد من التوت كما تريد ،
let alone
دعه وحده
a single one.
واحد.
Let's pick them up tomorrow. All right?
دعنا نلتقطهم غدا.  حسنا؟
All right.
حسنا.
Come.
يأتي.
Mother, let's go together.
أمي ، دعنا نذهب معا.
Why do both of you decide things so quickly?
لماذا يقرر كل منكما الأمور بهذه السرعة؟
Xiao only mentioned
شياو المذكورة فقط
a small wish.
أمنية صغيرة.
Can't we fulfill it?
لا يمكننا تحقيقه؟
Mother.
الأم.
- Miaomiao. - Mother.
- مياومياو.  - الأم.
Fine.
بخير.
Fine, Xiao.
بخير ، شياو.
I'll take you there.
سآخذك إلى هناك.
All right.
حسنا.
Why are you soaking wet?
لماذا أنت مبلل؟
Her Highness summoned me
استدعتني صاحبة السمو
and made me wait.
وجعلني أنتظر.
Qin Zuze must have been well-prepared
يجب أن يكون تشين زوز مستعدًا جيدًا
before returning.
قبل العودة.
Your life is in danger.
حياتك في خطر.
I have to congratulate you.
علي أن أهنئك.
What for?
لماذا؟
His Majesty said
قال جلالة الملك
Ninth Princess is interested in you that she travelled a lot.
الأميرة التاسعة مهتمة بك لأنها سافرت كثيرًا.
He is going to grant a marriage.
سوف يمنح الزواج.
What?
لما؟
No way.
مستحيل.
She was always angry at me.
كانت دائما غاضبة مني.
Is that a form of affection?
هل هذا شكل من أشكال المودة؟
Are you lying to me?
هل تكذب علي؟
I dare not fake an imperial edict.
لا أجرؤ على تزوير مرسوم إمبراطوري.
But...
لكن...
But she didn't act like that
لكنها لم تتصرف هكذا
when she liked you.
عندما كانت تحبك.
The nature of things
طبيعة الأشياء
changes according to the environment.
يتغير حسب البيئة.
If you apologize to me,
إذا اعتذرت لي ،
I will give you Shen Miao's portrait.
سأعطيك صورة شين مياو.
It was drawn few days ago.
تم رسمه قبل أيام قليلة.
Fresh out of the oven.
طازجة من الفرن.
Pei Yanzhen, you...
Pei Yanzhen ، أنت ...
How despicable.
كيف حقير.
How's Miao?
كيف حال مياو؟
She is doing great.
إنها تعمل بشكل رائع.
You miss them,
كنت تفوت عليها،
but they don't miss you.
لكنهم لا يشتاقون إليك.
Shen Xiao is close to Song Xiyuan like they are father and son.
شين شياو قريبة من Song Xiyuan مثل الأب والابن.
The three of them
ثلاثة منهم
are living happy lives.
يعيشون حياة سعيدة.
Oh.
أوه.
Our scouts said
قال الكشافة لدينا
confidants of Qin Zuze have arrived at Lingzhou City.
وصل المقربون من Qin Zuze إلى مدينة Lingzhou.
They pretended to be merchants and opened up shops near Shen's Residence.
تظاهروا بأنهم تجار وفتحوا متاجر بالقرب من Shen's Residence.
The Shen's Residence?
سكن شين؟
What are they planning for?
ما الذي يخططون له؟
We still don't know.
ما زلنا لا نعرف.
It's been three years.
لقد مرت ثلاث سنوات.
Perhaps Empress Dowager has forgotten Shen Miao and her child.
ربما نسيت الإمبراطورة الأرملة شين مياو وطفلها.
It might just be a misunderstanding.
قد يكون مجرد سوء فهم.
This concerns Miao and her child.
هذا يتعلق بمياو وطفلها.
We must be careful.
يجب أن نكون حذرين.
Xiao's birthday is coming soon.
عيد ميلاد Xiao قادم قريبًا.
Make the preparation. We'll go back.
قم بالتحضير.  سوف نعود.
But
لكن
if the Empress Dowager finds out...
إذا اكتشفت الإمبراطورة الأرملة ...
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Don't let other people find out.
لا تدع الآخرين يكتشفون ذلك.
This basket is for Grandfather and Grandmother.
هذه السلة للجد والجدة.
This basket is for Uncle.
هذه السلة للعم.
This big basket is for Mother.
هذه السلة الكبيرة للأم.
This small basket is for me.
هذه السلة الصغيرة لي.
What a happy day.
يا له من يوم سعيد.
Miaomiao.
مياومياو.
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
This orchard was my mother's betrothal gift.
كان هذا البستان هدية خطوبة والدتي.
Later, my father found out
لاحقًا ، اكتشف والدي الأمر
she liked to eat these fruits,
كانت تحب أن تأكل هذه الفاكهة ،
so he ordered someone to plant them.
فأمر أحدهم بزرعها.
Can the Song family eat so much?
هل يمكن لعائلة سونغ أن تأكل الكثير؟
No.
رقم.
What about the rest?
ماذا عن البقيه؟
We sold them.
بعناهم.
That's it.
هذا كل شيء.
It's exactly the same as what I said.
إنه بالضبط نفس ما قلته.
You don't understand the intention
أنت لا تفهم النية
behind this action.
وراء هذا العمل.
Lychees at Lingnan
ليتشي في لينجنان
are called "Concubine's Smile".
تسمى "ابتسامة محظية".
I want to give a name
اريد ان اعطي اسما
to the bayberries of Song's Orchard.
إلى التوت من بستان سونغ.
I will call them
سأتصل بهم
"Miaomiao's Smile".
"ابتسامة مياومياو".
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
Mother.
الأم.
I think it's very good.
أعتقد أنه جيد جدًا.
"Miaomiao's Smile".
"ابتسامة مياومياو".
Does Xiao smile as well?
هل يبتسم شياو كذلك؟
Xiao smiles.
شياو يبتسم.
I smile too.
أنا أبتسم أيضًا.
Xiyuan smiles!
شييوان يبتسم!
Stop!
قف!
Official Pei.
الرسمية بى.
It has been three years.
لقد مرت ثلاث سنوات.
There has been no news about you.
لم تكن هناك أخبار عنك.
Why did you
لماذا فعلت
choose to come back now?
اختر العودة الآن؟
Is it
فعلا
because of my son's birthday?
بسبب عيد ميلاد ابني؟
Master Song, you misunderstood.
سيد سونغ ، لقد أسيء فهمك.
I am
انا
only back here for work purposes.
فقط العودة هنا لأغراض العمل.
They say
يقولون
evil people have bad luck.
الأشرار لديهم حظ سيء.
The road here is wide,
الطريق هنا واسع ،
yet your wheels
بعد عجلاتك
still got stuck in the mud.
ما زلت عالقة في الوحل.
Seems like
يبدو مثل
the roads of Lingzhou
طرق Lingzhou
still don't welcome you.
ما زلت لا أرحب بك.
You should return to the capital
يجب أن تعود إلى العاصمة
and remain as a minister.
ويبقى وزيرا.
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
Sir, let's go.
سيدي ، دعنا نذهب.
Official Zhan is waiting for us.
المسؤول زان ينتظر منا.
"Miaomiao's Smile".
"ابتسامة مياومياو".
This name
هذا الإسم
is beautiful.
جميل.
Ask Zhan Yue to go to Zhezhe Tavern
اطلب من Zhan Yue الذهاب إلى Zhezhe Tavern
and check the situation.
وتحقق من الوضع.
(Shen Residence)
(سكن شين)
Pei Yanzhen
بي يانتشن
already left,
خرج مند زمن،
but why does he still annoy me?
لكن لماذا لا يزال يزعجني؟
No.
رقم.
I can't be affected by him.
لا يمكنني أن أتأثر به.
My business is going to be snatched.
سيتم خطف عملي.
Make money. I must think about making money.
جني المال.  يجب أن أفكر في كسب المال.
(Tavern)
(حانة)
Zhan Yue, how dare you.
Zhan Yue ، كيف تجرؤ.
What are you looking at?
الى ماذا تنظرين؟
You are acting sneakily.
أنت تتصرف بتستر.
I...
أنا...
Are you following me?
هل تتبعني؟
I know I'm handsome
أعلم أنني وسيم
but I have important things to do.
لكن لدي أشياء مهمة لأفعلها.
Farewell.
وداع.
Are you investigating a case?
هل تحقق في قضية؟
Is it fun?
هل هذا مسلي؟
Can you bring me along?
هل يمكنك اصطحابي معي؟
This is important.
هذا مهم.
There's no fun in it.
ليس هناك متعة في ذلك.
No.
رقم.
If you won't bring me,
إذا لم تحضرني ،
I will go inside the tavern and tell everyone
سأدخل الحانة وأخبر الجميع
that Guard Zhan is peeking.
أن الحارس زان يختلس النظر.
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
Dear customers, what do you want?
العملاء الأعزاء ماذا تريدون؟
A jar of wine and two dishes.
جرة من النبيذ وطبقين.
- Sure. - That's all?
- بالتأكيد.  - هذا كل شئ؟
You're so stingy.
أنت بخيل جدا.
Are you paying?
هل تدفع؟
Sir.
سيد.
Five minutes ago, he was...
قبل خمس دقائق ، كان ...
I'll pay.
سأدفع.
I want this, this and this.
اريد هذا وهذا وهذا وهذا.
Sure. Please wait.
بالتأكيد.  أرجو الإنتظار.
What are you looking at?
الى ماذا تنظرين؟
I don't like you.
أنا لا أحبك.
Who likes you?
من يحبك؟
Her?
لها؟
This is serious.
هذا أمر جاد.
Why are you jealous?
لماذا تغار؟
I'm not jealous.
أنا لست غيورًا.
Besides,
بجانب،
when did I like you?
متى أعجبت بك
No wonder you don't want me here.
لا عجب أنك لا تريدني هنا.
I'm insensible
أنا بلا وعي
and disturbed both of you.
وأزعجكما.
Causing trouble out of nothing.
التسبب في المتاعب من لا شيء.
You...
أنت...
Why are you so anxious?
لماذا انت قلق جدا؟
Why are you comparing her to me?
لماذا تقارنها بي؟
Besides,
بجانب،
when did I like you?
متى أعجبت بك
Why isn't Ninth Princess here yet?
لماذا لم تظهر الأميرة التاسعة هنا بعد؟
There's a new tavern called Zhezhe in the east of the city.
هناك حانة جديدة تسمى Zhezhe في شرق المدينة.
They snatched most of my business.
لقد استولوا على معظم أعمالي.
I made a few thousand taels less.
لقد صنعت بضعة آلاف من التيل أقل.
Do you need someone to cause trouble there?
هل تحتاج إلى شخص ما يسبب المتاعب هناك؟
Why don't I bring Zhan Yue?
لماذا لا أحضر Zhan Yue؟
No need.
لا حاجة.
I just
أنا فقط
want you to study
أريدك أن تدرس
their business methods.
أساليب عملهم.
At the same time,
في نفس الوقت،
we will look at how pretty
سننظر إلى مدى جمالها
their dancers are.
الراقصين هم.
See you at quarter to six tomorrow.
نراكم في الساعة السادسة والربع غدًا.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Why isn't she here yet?
لماذا هي ليست هنا بعد؟
You're finally here. Take the wine inside.
أنت هنا أخيرًا.  خذ النبيذ في الداخل.
This is exactly the same as the Master's seal of the Shen family.
هذا هو بالضبط نفس ختم السيد لعائلة شين.
We have been doing business with him for a few months.
لقد كنا نتعامل معه منذ بضعة أشهر.
There won't be a mistake.
لن يكون هناك خطأ.
With these few falsified ledgers,
مع هذه الدفاتر المزورة القليلة ،
we will soon be able to seize
سنكون قادرين قريبا على اغتنامها
the Shen family's assets.
أصول عائلة شين.
Keep this Shen family's seal well.
حافظ على ختم عائلة شين جيدًا.
Shen family's seal?
ختم عائلة شين؟
Who is it?
من هذا؟
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
It's just a cat.
إنها مجرد قطة.
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
We'll look somewhere else.
سنبحث في مكان آخر.
I think
أظن
your eyes look familiar.
عيناك تبدو مألوفة.
Are your legs fine?
هل ساقيك بخير؟
The red mark behind your ear
العلامة الحمراء خلف أذنك
looks familiar too.
يبدو مألوفًا أيضًا.
The callus on your left hand
المسمار على يدك اليسرى
suggests you are left-handed.
يقترح أنك أعسر.
I've never seen someone like you.
لم أرَ شخصًا مثلك أبدًا.
This is weird.
هذا غريب.
We never met before.
لم نلتق قط من قبل.
Your way of getting to know me
طريقتك في التعرف علي
is quite old-fashioned, Miss.
هو قديم الطراز يا آنسة.
You are perceptive.
أنت مدرك.
I am
انا
a girl.
فتاة.
I just learned to disguise myself.
لقد تعلمت فقط أن أتنكر.
How embarrassing.
كم هذا محرج.
May I know your name
هل لي أن أعرف إسمك
and where your house is?
واين منزلك
I will visit and thank you in the future.
سوف أزور وأشكرك في المستقبل.
Someone's here.
شخص ما هنا.
He looks like...
انه يشبه...
Pei Yanzhen?
بي يانتشن؟
He is just a scholar. He doesn't know martial arts.
إنه مجرد عالم.  لا يعرف فنون الدفاع عن النفس.
He is also not that kind.
هو أيضا ليس من هذا النوع.
It won't be him.
لن يكون هو.
He is not worthy for me to think of him.
إنه لا يستحق أن أفكر فيه.
(Ledger)
(موازنة)
I was interrupted by the Ninth Princess.
قاطعتني الأميرة التاسعة.
How was your investigation?
كيف كان تحقيقك؟
That tavern
تلك الحانة
is used to frame the Shen family indeed.
يستخدم لتأطير عائلة شين بالفعل.
Failing to report a large tribute,
عدم الإبلاغ عن جزية كبيرة ،
taking the royal court's land,
أخذ أرض الديوان الملكي ،
and involving themselves in the official trade of salt and iron.
وإشراك أنفسهم في التجارة الرسمية للملح والحديد.
These crimes
هذه الجرائم
are enough to put the whole Shen family to death.
تكفي لإعدام عائلة شين بأكملها.
Don't be afraid.
لا تخافوا.
It's me.
هذا أنا.
Miaomiao.
مياومياو.
Are you trying to scare me to death?
هل تحاول إخافتي حتى الموت؟
Father.
أب.
Where is our family's seal?
أين ختم عائلتنا؟
Seal?
عجل البحر؟
Where's my seal?
أين ختمي؟
It's over here.
إنه هنا.
The seal is here.
الختم هنا.
What's wrong?
ماالخطب؟
Someone forged
شخص ما مزورة
our family's seal at Zhezhe Tavern.
ختم عائلتنا في Zhezhe Tavern.
I don't know what their intention is.
لا أعرف ما هي نيتهم.
Is it true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
But...
لكن...
But tomorrow is Xiao's birthday.
ولكن غدا عيد ميلاد شياو.
Go back and rest.
العودة والراحة.
When this is over,
عندما ينتهي هذا ،
we'll investigate it.
سنحقق فيه.
Go back and sleep.
ارجع ونم.
Keep it well.
احتفظ بها بشكل جيد.
Xiao.
شياو.
I am here.
أنا هنا.
I don't care if Pei Yanzhen isn't here.
لا يهمني إذا لم يكن باي يانجين هنا.
But why is Song Xiyuan absent as well?
ولكن لماذا تغيب Song Xiyuan أيضًا؟
Xiao.
شياو.
Xiyuan.
شيوان.
This is your birthday present.
هذه هدية عيد ميلادك.
Do you like it?
هل أحببت ذلك؟
Xiao.
شياو.
This is also your birthday present.
هذه أيضًا هدية عيد ميلادك.
A lousy jade.
يشم رديء.
What a shame to be giving that.
يا له من عار أن نعطي ذلك.
The Shen family does have everything.
عائلة شين لديها كل شيء.
Xiao. If you like it,
شياو.  إذا أعجبك ذلك ،
you can take it.
تستطيع أخذها.
It's not appropriate.
ليس من المناسب.
Mother.
الأم.
I want this.
اريد هذا.
I want to make a bookmark with this.
أريد عمل إشارة مرجعية بهذا.
Young Master will grow to be someone capable
سوف ينمو السيد الشاب ليكون شخصًا قادرًا
with his love for literature.
مع حبه للأدب.
Xiao, don't play with that.
شياو ، لا تلعب مع ذلك.
Let's play with the cat.
هيا نلعب مع القط.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
It's Xiao's birthday.
إنه عيد ميلاد شياو.
Since he likes it, just take it.
بما أنه يحبها ، فقط خذها.
It might be useful
قد يكون مفيدا
in an important situation in the future.
في موقف مهم في المستقبل.
You prefer my birthday gift, right?
تفضل هدية عيد ميلادي ، أليس كذلك؟
Make yourself at home.
البيت بيتك.
I like it.
أحبها.
I knew it.
كنت أعرف.
Pei Yanzhen.
بي يانتشن.
Look.
نظرة.
It is smiling at you.
إنه يبتسم لك.
Miao.
مياو.
Xiao, look.
شياو ، انظر.
Was it you
هل كنت أنت
last night?
اخر مساء؟
Quick, tell your mother.
بسرعة ، أخبر والدتك.
Mother.
الأم.
Xiyuan said
قال شيوان
this cat is calling your name.
هذه القطة تنادي اسمك.
Meow.
مواء.
It really is.
هو حقا.
Mother, play with me.
أمي ، العب معي.
Mother, hurry.
أمي ، اسرعي.
Come here, Mother.
تعالي هنا يا أمي.
Is it cute?
هل هو لطيف؟
Give me.
أعطني.
I want to play with it.
اريد ان العب بها
I'm giving you both.
أنا أعطيكما كلاهما.
Sure. Pet it.
بالتأكيد.  الحيوانات الأليفة.
Give it.
اعطيها.
Let it play.
دعها تلعب.
Look.
نظرة.
Come and have a look.
يأتي وننظر لها.
Have a look at the rouge.
الق نظرة على أحمر الشفاه.
Why? Did you regret it?
لماذا ا؟  هل ندمت على ذلك؟
Why did you give such a precious pendant
لماذا أعطيت مثل هذه القلادة الثمينة
to Shen Miao then?
لشين مياو بعد ذلك؟
The Qin family is cunning.
عائلة تشين ماكرة.
Leaving that jade pendant
ترك قلادة اليشم تلك
might save Miao's life at least.
قد ينقذ حياة مياو على الأقل.
Let's go, Xiao.
لنذهب يا شياو.
Hurry up.
أسرع - بسرعة.
Pei Yanzhen!
بي يانتشن!
Come, Xiao.
تعال يا شياو.
Hurry.
عجل.
Follow me.
اتبعني.
I can't turn back right now.
لا يمكنني العودة الآن.
Pei Yanzhen!
بي يانتشن!
Pei Yanzhen, I have something to tell you!
بي يانتشن ، لدي ما أقوله لك!
Pei Yanzhen, why are you avoiding me?
Pei Yanzhen ، لماذا تتجنبني؟
Pei Yanzhen!
بي يانتشن!
Benefactor.
فاعل خير.
Who are you calling?
من تنادي؟
You made a mistake.
لقد ارتكبت خطأ.
Zhan Yue.
زان يو.
Why did he ignore me?
لماذا تجاهلني؟
Has he been avoiding me?
هل كان يتجنبني؟
He returned to Lingzhou in secret.
عاد إلى Lingzhou في الخفاء.
He left because his work is done.
غادر لأن عمله انتهى.
Besides, why should he avoid you?
علاوة على ذلك ، لماذا يتجنبك؟
He has been
وقال انه تم
lying to me for the past three years.
يكذب علي في السنوات الثلاث الماضية.
He didn't even look for you. How could he lie to you?
لم يبحث عنك حتى.  كيف يمكنه أن يكذب عليك؟
Mother.
الأم.
Didn't you say I could always be safe
ألم تقل بإمكاني أن أكون دائمًا بأمان
because I met a benefactor?
لأنني قابلت فاعل خير؟
When I fell in the water, fell down from the tree
عندما سقطت في الماء ، سقطت من الشجرة
and got lost once,
وضاعت مرة واحدة ،
it was this man who helped me.
كان هذا الرجل هو الذي ساعدني.
It's nothing much.
لا شيء كثيرًا.
Did Pei Yanzhen
هل بى يانتشن
ask you to protect us in secret?
أطلب منك أن تحمينا في الخفاء؟
How can you say he isn't lying?
كيف يمكنك القول أنه لا يكذب؟
He kept hiding and won't give up.
ظل يختبئ ولن يستسلم.
He even saved me at the tavern last night.
حتى أنه أنقذني في الحانة الليلة الماضية.
What does he want?
ماذا يريد؟
Pei Yanzhen's intention is complicated.
نية بي يانتشن معقدة.
I wouldn't know.
لا أعرف.
Zhan Yue!
زان يو!
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
(Daqing Gate)
(بوابة داتشينغ)
when I returned to Lingzhou to visit my family,
عندما عدت إلى Lingzhou لزيارة عائلتي ،
I accidentally found out
اكتشفت بالصدفة
someone forging seals and documents
شخص ما تزوير الأختام والمستندات
to frame the Shen family.
لتأطير عائلة شين.
Please investigate it.
يرجى التحقيق فيه.
Everyone knows
الجميع يعلم
your relationship with the Shen family.
علاقتك مع عائلة شين.
Are you doing this for personal reason
هل تفعل هذا لسبب شخصي
or for justice?
أم من أجل العدالة؟
The Shen family is reputable in Lingzhou
تتمتع عائلة شين بسمعة طيبة في لينجزهو
yet they are still being framed.
ومع ذلك لا يزال يتم تأطيرهم.
If we are going to ignore this,
إذا كنا سنتجاهل هذا ،
wouldn't it put everyone at risk
لن يعرض الجميع للخطر
and cause chaos among people?
وتسبب الفوضى بين الناس؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
You must
يجب عليك أن
investigate this.
تحقق في هذا.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
I'll follow your suggestion, Uncle.
سأتبع اقتراحك يا عمي.
Yes.
نعم.
(Tavern)
(حانة)
Pei Yanzhen helped us plead for our innocence
ساعدنا Pei Yanzhen في الدفاع عن براءتنا
(Tavern) in the morning,
(الحانة) في الصباح ،
and the tavern got cleaned out in the afternoon.
وتم تنظيف الحانة في فترة ما بعد الظهر.
I'm afraid we can't find any more clues.
أخشى أنه لا يمكننا العثور على أي أدلة أخرى.
What clues do you need?
ما القرائن التي تحتاجها؟
If the Shen family's assets go to the treasury,
إذا ذهبت أصول عائلة شين إلى الخزينة ،
the person who benefits the most is General Qin
الشخص الذي يستفيد أكثر هو الجنرال تشين
apart from the Empress Dowager.
بصرف النظر عن الإمبراطورة الأرملة.
There are no more suspects.
ليس هناك المزيد من المشتبه بهم.
Thankfully, Pei Yanzhen is around.
لحسن الحظ ، Pei Yanzhen موجود.
He wouldn't have done this
لم يكن ليفعل هذا
if he didn't have lingering feelings for you.
إذا لم يكن لديه مشاعر باقية تجاهك.
If he does have feelings for you,
إذا كان لديه مشاعر تجاهك ،
why did he go missing for three years?
لماذا اختفى لمدة ثلاث سنوات؟
In order to help the society,
من أجل مساعدة المجتمع ،
he must have offended many nobles for the past three years.
لا بد أنه أساء إلى العديد من النبلاء خلال السنوات الثلاث الماضية.
He is a righteous person.
إنه شخص صالح.
I'm sure he has to do this
أنا متأكد من أنه يجب عليه القيام بذلك
because he doesn't want to involve our family.
لأنه لا يريد إشراك عائلتنا.
(I knew it)
(كنت أعرف)
(since I'm too good to be given up.)
(لأنني أفضل من أن أتخلى عنها).
Brother.
شقيق.
How can you let His Majesty investigate this?
كيف يمكنك أن تدع جلالة الملك يحقق في هذا؟
If he finds out we are the ones behind it...
إذا اكتشف أننا وراءها ...
It's nothing much.
لا شيء كثيرًا.
The people they captured
الأشخاص الذين أسروا
are the Qin family's men who aren't afraid of death.
هم رجال عائلة تشين الذين لا يخافون الموت.
In the end,
بالنهايه،
all witnesses will be dead and they won't find anything.
سيموت جميع الشهود ولن يجدوا شيئًا.
We spent a lot of effort.
لقد بذلنا الكثير من الجهد.
I didn't expect
لم أتوقع
Pei Yanzhen to spoil our plan near the end.
Pei Yanzhen لإفساد خطتنا قرب النهاية.
What a cunning person.
يا له من شخص ماكر.
They divorced for three years,
طلقوا ثلاث سنوات ،
but he still can't forget the Shen family.
لكنه لا يزال لا ينسى عائلة شين.
It's nothing.
إنه لاشيء.
We have Pei Yanzhen's weakness now.
لدينا ضعف Pei Yanzhen الآن.
There's nothing difficult about him.
لا يوجد شيء صعب فيه.
Brother, you mean...
أخي تقصد ...
My daughter Qin Miuzhen
ابنتي تشين ميوزين
is at the age of marriage.
في سن الزواج.
If you grant a marriage,
إذا تزوجت ،
do you think Pei Yanzhen will go against your edict
هل تعتقد أن باي يانتشن سوف يتعارض مع مرسومك
with his love for Shen Miao?
مع حبه لشين مياو؟
I will see what he says.
سأرى ما يقول.
If it's true,
إذا كان هذا صحيحا،
I can get rid of him.
يمكنني التخلص منه.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I will never marry Qin Miuzhen.
لن أتزوج أبدا من تشين ميوزين.
I knew you would say that.
أعلم بأنك كنت ستقول ذلك.
But rejecting a marriage is punishable by death.
لكن رفض الزواج يعاقب عليه بالإعدام.
Doing that is what they want.
فعل هذا هو ما يريدون.
I might not be able to protect you
قد لا أتمكن من حمايتك
even if I'm the emperor.
حتى لو كنت أنا الإمبراطور.
If you die, who will protect Shen Miao and her son?
إذا مت ، من سيحمي شين مياو وابنها؟
Pei Yanzhen.
بي يانتشن.
There's always hope as long as you are still alive.
هناك دائما أمل طالما أنك لا تزال على قيد الحياة.
The marriage is a delaying tactic.
الزواج هو تكتيك المماطلة.
You can get a divorce later.
يمكنك الحصول على الطلاق لاحقا.
Even if I marry Qin Miuzhen,
حتى لو تزوجت من تشين ميوزين ،
the Qin family won't spare everyone.
لن تدخر عائلة تشين الجميع.
However, you will buy enough time
ومع ذلك ، سوف تشتري وقتًا كافيًا
and have an opportunity to hit the enemy on the inside.
ولديك فرصة لضرب العدو من الداخل.
When you have the evidence of Qin family's crime,
عندما يكون لديك دليل على جريمة عائلة تشين ،
you can arrest them all.
يمكنك اعتقالهم جميعًا.
Yanzhen.
يانتشن.
Even if you don't think about yourself,
حتى لو كنت لا تفكر في نفسك ،
you should think about Shen Miao and her son.
يجب أن تفكر في شين مياو وابنها.
Do you think Mother
هل تعتقد الأم
will spare the Shen family and your parents
سوف تجنيب عائلة شين ووالديك
after you die?
بعد موتك
I think
أظن
there are other solutions
هناك حلول أخرى
as long as the decision isn't final.
طالما أن القرار ليس نهائيًا.
I can give you time
يمكنني أن أعطيك الوقت
but the Qin family won't.
لكن عائلة تشين لن تفعل ذلك.
The order for the marriage has not been issued.
لم يصدر أمر الزواج.
But Mother has ordered
لكن الأم أمرت
Qin Miuzhen to return to Lingzhou and prepare for the wedding.
Qin Miuzhen للعودة إلى Lingzhou والاستعداد لحفل الزفاف.
She wanted you to be the escort.
أرادت أن تكون المرافقة.
Yanzhen. Everything is related.
يانتشن.  كل شيء مرتبط.
You have to think carefully.
عليك أن تفكر مليا.
How is it? Is it fine?
كيف هذا؟  هل الامر على ما يرام؟
You've asked me 800 times.
لقد سألتني 800 مرة.
You are charming.
انت وسيم.
Miss. That's Official Pei's boat.
أنسة ، هذا هو قارب الرسمية باي.
Pei Yanzhen.
بي يانتشن.
I appreciate
أنا أقدر
your kindness.
لطفك.
To protected us, three years ago
لحمايتنا ، منذ ثلاث سنوات
you asked Zhan Yue to protect us
لقد طلبت من Zhan Yue حمايتنا
even when you went to the city alone.
حتى عندما ذهبت إلى المدينة بمفردك.
A few days ago, you even went to the tavern in the middle of the night
قبل أيام قليلة ذهبت إلى الحانة في منتصف الليل
to clear Shen family's name.
لمسح اسم عائلة شين.
Pei Yanzhen.
بي يانتشن.
Don't bear everything all by yourself anymore.
لا تتحمل كل شيء بنفسك بعد الآن.
I'll be here with you.
سأكون هنا معك.
We'll shoulder everything together.
سنحمل كل شيء معًا.
Shall we?
هلا فعلنا؟
Yanzhen. I fell asleep.
يانتشن.  غطت فى النوم.
Why didn't you wake me up?
لماذا لم توقظني؟
The cousin from the Qin family?
ابن العم من عائلة تشين؟
It's been a long time, Jiu.
لقد مر وقت طويل ، جيو.
(Qin Miuzhen) I wouldn't have met you again
(تشين ميوزين) لم أكن لألتقي بك مرة أخرى
without Official Pei's invitation.
بدون دعوة رسمية من Pei.
That's impossible.
هذا مستحيل.
Pei Yanzhen doesn't like you.
Pei Yanzhen لا تحبك.
Who does he like?
من يحب؟
You
أنت
or her?
او هي؟
Shen Miao, don't listen to her nonsense.
شين مياو ، لا تستمع إلى هرائها.
She is good at sowing discord.
إنها جيدة في زرع الفتنة.
I'm sure it's a one-sided love.
أنا متأكد من أنه حب من طرف واحد.
She just followed him shamelessly.
لقد تبعته فقط دون خجل.
Didn't you do the same back then?
ألم تفعل الشيء نفسه في ذلك الوقت؟
You...
أنت...
Pei Yanzhen, let's not talk about Miss Qin for now.
Pei Yanzhen ، دعنا لا نتحدث عن Miss Qin في الوقت الحالي.
Do you really like me?
هل انت حقا معجب بي؟
I protected Shen Xiao in secret
لقد قمت بحماية شين شياو في الخفاء
because I still think
لأنني ما زلت أعتقد
Xiao is my child
شياو هو طفلي
regardless of how others think.
بغض النظر عن طريقة تفكير الآخرين.
I helped the Shen family in the royal court
لقد ساعدت عائلة شين في البلاط الملكي
because it was the right thing to do.
لأنه كان الشيء الصحيح الذي ينبغي عمله.
Even if it happens to someone else,
حتى لو حدث ذلك لشخص آخر ،
I will also help them.
سوف اساعدهم ايضا
Every incident
كل حادثة
is not related to you.
لا علاقة لك.
Fine.
بخير.
Great.
رائعة.
Is it because of her?
هل بسببها؟
♪They say that true love is something to be envious of♪
♪ يقولون أن الحب الحقيقي شيء يحسدون عليه ♪
Shen Miao!
شين مياو!
♪Have you seen all the love words in a play?♪
♪ هل رأيت كل كلمات الحب في مسرحية؟
Official Pei.
الرسمية بى.
Pei Yanzhen!
بي يانتشن!
- Go after her! - The father of Miss Shen's child
- اذهب ورائها!  - والد طفل الآنسة شين
is still unknown.
لا يزال مجهولا.
- How dare she goes after Minister Pei. - To Shen's Residence.
- كيف تجرؤ على ملاحقة الوزير باي.  - في سكن شين.
Right.
حق.
Miss Shen is flattering herself.
الآنسة شين تملق نفسها.
- She's flattering herself. - Miss!
- إنها تملق نفسها.  - يفتقد!
She's flattering herself.
إنها تملق نفسها.
Miss?
يفتقد؟
Miss!
يفتقد!
♪Only love can burn you up and get your heart pumping♪
♪ الحب وحده هو الذي يحرقك ويجعل قلبك ينبض ♪
♪I heard the cuckoo again just like the time I first saw you♪
♪ سمعت الوقواق مرة أخرى مثلما رأيتك لأول مرة
♪I long for you again when I sit on a swing under the moon♪
أشتاق إليك مرة أخرى عندما أجلس على أرجوحة تحت القمر
We are here.
نحن هنا.
What is this place?
ما هذا المكان؟
It's me, Madam.
إنه أنا ، سيدتي.
Tie Niu.
التعادل نيو.
Why is it you?
لماذا انت
Why did you put up this act?
لماذا قمت بهذا الفعل؟
Master sees that you are in a bad mood
يرى المعلم أنك في حالة مزاجية سيئة
and wanted to surprise you.
وأردت أن يفاجئك.
What kind of surprise?
أي نوع من المفاجأة؟
Send me back.
أعدني.
Return it!
أعده!
If you want it,
اذا كنت تريده،
just follow me.
اتبعني فقط.
Tie Niu!
التعادل نيو!
Tie Niu, return it!
التعادل نيو ، إعادته!
Tie Niu.
التعادل نيو.
Tie Niu!
التعادل نيو!
You...
أنت...
Are you charmed?
هل انت ساحر؟
Are you drunk?
هل انت سكران؟
Tie Niu. Tie Niu!
التعادل نيو. التعادل نيو!
Since you are here,
بما أنك هنا
I've prepared some dishes.
لقد أعددت بعض الأطباق.
Let's have a drink.
لنشرب.
You are really drunk.
أنت ثمل حقًا.
I'll ask Tie Niu to send you back.
سأطلب من Tie Niu إعادتك.
Tie Niu!
التعادل نيو!
I'm not drunk.
أنا لست مخمورا.
Fine.
بخير.
I'm drunk.
أنا في حالة سكر.
I am very drunk.
أنا في حالة سكر جدا.
I'm so drunk that I have no strength.
أنا في حالة سكر لدرجة أنني لا أملك القوة.
I'm so drunk
أنا حتى في حالة سكر
that I'm going to fall into the river.
أنني سأقع في النهر.
Miaomiao!
مياومياو!
Hold me.
أمسكني.
Miaomiao, I can't swim!
مياومياو ، لا أستطيع السباحة!
Help me!
ساعدني!
Miao...
مياو ...
Ladies like you
سيدات مثلك
are getting harder to please nowadays.
أصبح من الصعب إرضاء هذه الأيام.
You won't even hold me
لن تمسكني حتى
after you see me being drunk.
بعد أن تراني وأنا في حالة سكر.
You won't treat me like how you treat Pei Yanzhen.
لن تعاملني كما تعامل بي يانتشن.
I wonder if you are
أتساءل إذا كنت كذلك
purposely fooling me
خداع لي عمدا
like Pei Yanzhen,
مثل Pei Yanzhen ،
just to see me embarrass myself.
لمجرد رؤيتي أحرج نفسي.
Yanzhen is definitely
يانتشن بالتأكيد
not a good person.
ليس شخصا جيدا.
But look at me.
لكن انظر إلي.
For the past three years...
على مدى السنوات الثلاث الماضية ...
Aren't we drinking?
لا نشرب؟
Falling in love
الوقوع في الحب
hurts the body and mind.
يؤذي الجسم والعقل.
It's better to become someone heartless
من الأفضل أن تصبح شخصًا بلا قلب
and make the most of today.
وتحقيق أقصى استفادة من اليوم.
Let's get drunk and forget our sorrows.
دعونا نسكر وننسى أحزاننا.
Cheers.
هتافات.
Leave.
غادر.
Yes.
نعم.
Your Highness summoned me so late at night.
سموك استدعاني في وقت متأخر من الليل.
I wonder what kind of emergency it is.
أتساءل ما هو نوع الطوارئ.
Brother.
شقيق.
Pei Yanzhen agreed
وافق باي يانتشن
to escort Zhen to Lingzhou.
لمرافقة Zhen إلى Lingzhou.
I don't get it.
انا لم احصل عليها.
What is he trying to do?
ما هو انه يحاول القيام به؟
He is only doing it
هو يفعل ذلك فقط
to confuse us
لإرباكنا
and delay for a few days.
والتأخير لبضعة أيام.
But he will meet Shen Miao
لكنه سيلتقي شين مياو
when he returns to Lingzhou.
عندما عاد إلى Lingzhou.
It will bring out his feelings for her.
سوف يبرز مشاعره لها.
What if he really marries Zhen
ماذا لو تزوج حقا من زين
to protect his life and assets?
لحماية حياته وأصوله؟
Then, she will be
ثم ستكون
the spy and assassin
الجاسوس والقاتل
we plant beside Pei Yanzhen.
نزرع بجانب Pei Yanzhen.
Your Highness, please draft the edict to grant the marriage
صاحب السمو ، يرجى صياغة مرسوم الزواج
according to our original plan.
وفقًا لخطتنا الأصلية.
If he rejects the marriage,
إذا رفض الزواج ،
we will be able to get rid of him.
سنتمكن من التخلص منه.
It's all over no matter what happens.
انتهى الأمر بغض النظر عما يحدث.
Pei Yanzhen
بي يانتشن
will no longer trouble us.
لن تزعجنا بعد الآن.
Miss Shen's confession today
اعتراف الآنسة شين اليوم
is really moving.
حقا تتحرك.
To protected us, three years ago
لحمايتنا ، منذ ثلاث سنوات
you asked Zhan Yue to protect us
لقد طلبت من Zhan Yue حمايتنا
even when you went to the city alone.
حتى عندما ذهبت إلى المدينة بمفردك.
A few days ago, you even went to the tavern in the middle of the night
قبل أيام قليلة ذهبت إلى الحانة في منتصف الليل
to clear the Shen family's name.
لمسح اسم عائلة شين.
Pei Yanzhen.
بي يانتشن.
Don't bear everything all by yourself anymore.
لا تتحمل كل شيء بنفسك بعد الآن.
I'll be here with you.
سأكون هنا معك.
We'll shoulder everything together.
سنحمل كل شيء معًا.
Shall we?
هلا فعلنا؟
If I didn't know about her relationship
إذا لم أكن أعرف عن علاقتها
with Song Xiyuan in the last three years
مع Song Xiyuan في السنوات الثلاث الماضية
and her indecent personality,
وشخصيتها غير اللائقة ،
I would really believe her.
سوف أصدقها حقا.
Pei Yanzhen.
بي يانتشن.
Shen Miao is just a merchant's daughter.
شين مياو هي مجرد ابنة تاجر.
She has...
انها لديها...
Congratulations, Official Pei.
مبروك ، الرسمية باي.
You are favored by many beautiful ladies,
أنت مفضل من قبل العديد من السيدات الجميلات ،
yet you don't know how to cherish them.
لكنك لا تعرف كيف تعتز بهم.
Where is Shen Miao?
أين شين مياو؟
It has been three years.
لقد مرت ثلاث سنوات.
Shen Miao is already
شين مياو بالفعل
favoring Song Xiyuan now.
لصالح Song Xiyuan الآن.
What you did today
ماذا فعلت اليوم
broke her heart even more.
كسر قلبها أكثر.
Even if you know where she is,
حتى لو كنت تعرف مكانها ،
you still have to marry Qin Miuzhen.
لا يزال عليك الزواج من تشين ميوزين.
♪There are many devoted lovers in the mortal world♪
هناك العديد من العشاق المخلصين في العالم الفاني
♪It's hard to understand love♪
♪ من الصعب أن تفهم الحب ♪
♪If I have another chance, I won't be late again♪
♪ إذا سنحت لي فرصة أخرى ، فلن أتأخر مرة أخرى
♪All I wish is for you to be well♪
♪ كل ما أتمناه هو أن تكوني بخير
♪Don't ask me if this is worth it♪
♪ لا تسألني إذا كان هذا يستحق ذلك ♪
♪However, love is♪
لكن الحب هو ♪
♪Turning into lovesickness when it deepens into your heart♪
تتحول إلى غشاوة عندما تتعمق في قلبك
♪Even life and death can't frighten me♪
♪ حتى الحياة والموت لا يمكن أن تخيفني
♪I've been through the good times and bad times♪
♪ لقد مررت بأوقات طيبة وأخرى سيئة ♪
♪But the person I've been waiting for is not aware of it♪
♪ لكن الشخص الذي كنت أنتظره ليس على علم بذلك
♪There's an unfinished story between you and me♪
♪ هناك قصة غير منتهية بيني وبينك
♪How am I supposed to continue my life?♪
♪ كيف لي أن أكمل حياتي؟
♪The moon rises and sets, a day has passed♪
القمر يطلع ويغيب مضى يوم ♪
♪I just want to protect you until old ages♪
♪ أريد فقط أن أحميك حتى الشيخوخة ♪
♪And make a vow about you♪
وأقطع نذرًا عنك
♪I'm willing to be obsessed with you♪
♪ أنا على استعداد لأن أكون مهووسًا بك ♪
♪I wish we could be together in our next lifes♪
♪ أتمنى أن نكون معًا في حياتنا القادمة